David Dietz Papers
David Dietz Papers
- Correspondence
  - Royal Astronomical Society (Box 18)
  - Royal Astronomical Society of Canada (Box 18)
  - Royal Societies Club (Box 18)
  - Ruarck, Robert C. (Box 18)
  - Rubber Manufacturers Association (Box 18)
  - Rudin, Jacob P. (Rabbi) (Box 18)
  - Rusk, Howard A. (Dr.) (Box 18)
  - Russell, James (Box 18)
  - Russell Sage Foundation (Box 18)
  - Russian War Relief (Box 18)
  - Rutgers University (Box 18)
  - Ryan, Frank J. (Box 18)
  - Rychlik, Charles V. (Box 18)
  - S, general, 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Sabatini Ristorante (Box 18)
  - Sabin, Albert B. (Dr.) (Box 18)
  - Sack, Leo R. (Box 18)
  - Saint Louis Star-Times (Box 18)
  - Saint Martin's Press (Box 18)
  - Saks Fifth Avenue (Box 28)
  - Salisbury, Franklin C. (Box 18)
  - Salk, Jonas E. (Dr.) (Box 19)
  - Salter, Lawrence C. (Box 28)
  - Sandoz Pharmaceuticals (Box 19)
  - San Francisco (Box 28)
  - Santa Fe Railroad (Box 19)
  - Sargeant, Howland H. (National Science Fund) (Box 19)
  - Sarisky, Michael (Box 19)
  - Sarton, George (Dr.) (Box 28)
  - Saturday Evening Post (Box 28)
  - [W. B.] Saunders Company (Box 19)
  - Savas, John (Box 28)
  - Saxbe, William B. (Congressman) (Box 19)
  - Schacht, Max M. (Box 19)
  - Scheele, Leonard (Box 28)
  - Schenley, Laboratories (Box 28)
  - Schering Corporation (Box 19)
  - Schmeh, Carl (Box 19)
  - Schneider, Charles (Box 19)
  - Scholastic Magazines (Box 28)
  - [A.] Schulman, Incorporated (Box 28)
  - Schuman, Harry (Box 28)
  - Schwartz, Joan (Box 19)
  - Science letters (Box 19)
  - Science Research Associates (Box 28)
  - Science Service (Box 19)
  - Scientific American (Box 19)
  - Scott, Kenneth D. (Box 19)
  - [Charles] Scribner's Sons (Box 19)
  - Scripps, Charles E. (Box 19)
  - Scripps Foundation for Research in Population Problems (Box 28)
  - Scripps, Robert P. (Box 19)
  - Scripps, Mrs. Robert P. (Box 19)
  - Scripps-Howard Editors, 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Scripps-Howard Foundation (Box 19)
  - Scripps-Howard Investment Company (Box 19)
  - Scripps-Howard News (Box 19)
  - Scripps-Howard News, July, 1964; article (Box 19)
  - Scripps-Howard Newspaper Alliance (Box 19)
  - Scripps-Howard Newspapers (Box 19)
  - Scripps Institution of Oceanography (Box 19)
  - Sears Publishing Company, J. H. Sears, President (Box 19)
  - Sears Publishing Company, Karl E. Harriman, Vice President (Box 19)
  - Sears Publishing Company, P. A. Murkland, Vice President (Box 19)
  - See, T. T. J. (Dr.) (Box 19)
  - Seely, Warner (Warner and Swasey Company) (Box 19)
  - Seaborg, Glenn T. (Dr.) (Box 19)
  - Selker, S. W. (Box 19)
  - Seltzer, Louis B. (Box 19)
    See also Dietz, David: Memos to L. B. S.
  - Selye, Hans (Dr.) (Box 19)
  - Severence, John L. (Box 19)
  - Shaker Heights (City) (Box 19)
  - Shaker Heights Board of Education (Box 19)
  - Shaker Heights Library Board (Box 19)
  - Shaker Heights Library Board, 1970- (Box 20)
  - Shaker Heights Library Board, 1967-1969 (Box 28)
  - Shaker Lakes (Box 20)
  - Shaker Library Tax Levy (Box 20)
  - Shankland, Robert S. (Dr.) (Box 20)
  - Shapely, Harlow (Box 20)
  - Shaw, Norman (Box 20)
  - Shearer, Douglas G. (Box 28)
  - Sheffield Farms Company, 2 folders (Box 20)
  - Shell Oil Company, 2 folders (Box 20)
  - Shell Oil Company, additional material (Box 28)
  - Shepherd, Arthur (Box 28)
  - Sheraton-Cleveland Hotel (Box 20)
  - Shoenfield, Alan ( Detroit News science editor) (Box 20)
  - Shulman, Alix (Box 20)
  - [Louis] Shurr Agency (Box 20)
  - Sidlo, Thomas L. (Box 20)
  - Sidlo, Thomas L., additional material (Box 28)
  - Siegel, A. L. (Box 20)
  - Siegel, Norman (Box 29)
  - Sigel, Sam (Box 20)
  - Sigerist, Henry E. (Johns Hopkins University) (Box 20)
  - Sigma Delta Chi, 3 folders (Box 20)
  - Sigma Delta Chi, additional material (Box 29)
  - Sigma Xi, 2 folders (Box 20)
  - Sikes, John (Box 20)
  - Silbert, Samuel H. (Judge) (Box 20)
  - Sill, Alex N. (Box 20)
  - Silver, Abba Hillel (Rabbi) (Box 20)
  - Silverman, Milton (Box 29)
  - Silverman, Myron (Rabbi) (Box 20)
  - Simon, Max (Box 29)
  - Simon and Schuster (Box 20)
  - Simmons, James Stevens (Brigadier General) (Box 20)
  - Sky and Telescope (Box 20)
  - Sloan, H. G. (Dr.) (Box 20)
  - [Wiliam] Sloane Associates Incorporated (Box 29)
  - Smith, Allard (Box 20)
  - Smith, Earl (Major) (Box 29)
  - Smith Jr., Harry W. (Box 20)
  - Smith, Pauline (Box 20)
  - Smith, Theobald (Box 20)
  - Smithsonian Astrophysical Observatory (Box 20)
  - Smithsonian Institution (Box 20)
  - Smithton, Harry L. (Box 20)
  - Snadjr, Robert I. (Box 29)
  - Snider, Arthur J. (Box 20)
  - [Foster D.] Snell, Incorporated (Box 20)
  - Snyder, Mary Rennels (Box 29)
  - Social Science Research Council (Box 20)
  - Society for the History of Techology (Box 20)
  - Society for the Study of Inebriety (Box 20)
  - Sollins, I. V. (Dr.) (Box 20)
  - Sollmann, Torald (Dr.) (Box 20)
  - Sorrells, John H., 1938- (Box 20)
  - Sorrells, John H. (Executive Editor) (Box 20)
  - Sorrells, John H., 1942- (Box 20)
  - Southwest Center for Advanced Studies (Box 20)
  - Sowers, George B. (Box 20)
  - Sowers, George B., additional material (Box 29)
  - Speaking engagements (Box 21)
  - Spencer, Steven M. (Box 21)
  - Spies, Tom D. (M.D.) (Box 29)
  - Spira, Philip (Box 21)
  - Spitalny, Maurice (Box 21)
  - Spreng, Dwight S. (Dr.) (Box 21)
  - Stafford, Jane (Box 21)
  - Stafford, Jane, additional material (Box 29)
  - Stage Door Canteen of Cleveland (Box 21)
  - Stahl, William M. (New York University) (Box 21)
  - Stainless Metals, Incorporated (Box 21)
  - Stamford Jewish Center (Box 21)
  - Standard Oil Company of New Jersey (Box 21)
  - Standard Oil Company (Box 21)
  - Stanford Research Institute (Box 21)
  - Stanford University (Box 21)
  - Stanley, W. M. (Box 21)
  - Starbuck, A. (Professor, Iowa State College) (Box 21)
  - State Department (Box 29)
  - State Natural History Survey, Urbana, Illinois (Box 21)
  - Stauffner, L. H. (Box 21)
  - Steger Jr., Evan (Box 21)
  - Steiner, Harry (Box 21)
  - Stenzel, Werner (Box 21)
  - Stephan, John C. (Box 21)
  - Stephens, J. B. (Box 21)
  - Stephenson, C. S. (Captain), 1942- (Box 21)
  - Stephenson, C. S. (Captain), Washington, D. C. (Box 21)
  - Sterbercz, Irene (Box 29)
  - Stern, G. W. (Dr.) (Box 21)
  - Stetson, Harlan T. (Box 29)
  - Stewart-Warner Corporation (Box 21)
  - Stice, Lois (Box 29)
  - Stieglitz, Julius (University of Chicago) (Box 21)
  - Stokely, James (Box 21)
  - Stone, Ruth T. (Box 21)
  - Stone, Walker (Box 21)
  - Stoner, Willard C. (M.D.) (Box 21)
  - Stormer, Carl (Professor) (Box 21)
  - Storms, Albert B. (President, Baldwin Wallace College) (Box 21)
  - Stotter, Ray (Box 21)
  - Stout, Wilbur (Box 21)
  - Stratford Company (Box 21)
  - Strauss, Lewis L. (Admiral) (Box 21)
  - Streem, Jerome A. (Dr.) (Box 29)
  - Strong, Cobb and Company Incorporated (Box 29)
  - Strong, George F. (Box 21)
  - Struve, Otto (Box 29)
  - Sturges, Kenneth (Community Fund) (Box 21)
  - Suburban Temple (Box 21)
  - Sugar Research Foundation (Box 21)
  - Surgeon General Office, travel orders (Box 21)
  - Surman, Mrs. Frank H. (Box 21)
  - Sutton, Richard M. (Dr.) (Box 29)
  - Sutton, Rodney S. (Box 21)
  - Swan-Finch Oil Corporation (Box 21)
  - Swann, W.F.G. (Dr.) (Box 21)
  - Swasey, Ambrose (Box 21)
  - Swedish American Line (Box 21)
  - Swedish Information Bureau (Box 21)
  - Swift, Otis Peabody (Box 21)
  - Swift, R. W. (Box 21)
  - Swiss National Tourist Office (Box 21)
  - Swiss Review of World Affairs (Box 21)
  - Synagogue Council of America (Box 21)
  - Syndicated column (Box 21)
  - Syntex Laboratories (Box 21)
  - Syracuse University, 3 folders (Box 21)
  - Szabadsag (Box 22)
  - Szilard, Leo (Box 22)
  - TRW, Incorporated (Box 22)
  - Taber, Herman (Box 22)
  - Taft, Kingsley A. (Box 22)
  - Taft, Robert A. (Senator) (Box 22)
  - Taft Jr., Robert (Box 22)
  - Taft, William (Senator) (Box 22)
  - Talcott, Dora (Box 22)
  - Talley, Robert (Box 22)
  - Tallmadge, Ellenor, 2 folders (Box 22)
  - Talmey, Max (Dr.) (Box 22)
  - Tanner, Bill (Box 22)
  - Tassman, Gustav (Dr.) (Box 22)
  - Taylor, Eugene J. (Box 22)
  - Taylor, Graves (Box 22)
  - Taylor, Griffith (Dr.) (University of Chicago) (Box 22)
  - Taylor, Walter P. (United States Department of Agriculture) (Box 22)
  - Technicon (Box 22)
  - Tel-Aviv (Box 22)
  - Telling-Belle Vernon Company (Box 22)
  - Tennessee Valley Authority (Box 29)
  - Thacker, Earl M. (Box 22)
  - Thackrey, T. C. (Box 22)
  - Thayer, Jack G. (Box 22)
  - Thomas, Lowell (Box 22)
  - Thomas, Vincent C. (Dr.) (Box 29)
  - Thompson, Don (Wellston, Oklahoma) (Box 22)
  - [J. Walter] Thompson Company, 2 folders (Box 22)
  - [J. Walter] Thompson Company, additional material (Box 29)
  - Thompson, Lockwood (Box 22)
  - Thompson, Warren S. (Box 22)
  - Thompson, Warren S., additional material (Box 29)
  - Thone, Frank (Box 29)
  - Thorndike, Lynn (Dr.) (Box 29)
  - Thornton Jr., W. W. (Box 22)
  - Thornton, Willis (Box 29)
  - Thum, E. E. (Box 29)
  - Thwing, Charles F. (Dr.) (Box 22)
  - Tietz, Julius B. (Box 22)
  - Till, Kay (Box 22)
  - Time Magazine (Box 22)
  - Tishman, Robert V. (Box 22)
  - Tivoli Gardens (Box 22)
  - Todd, T. Wingate (Dr.) (Box 22)
  - Tolles, Hogsett and Ginn (Box 22)
  - Tolman, Richard C. (Box 22)
  - Tombaugh, Clyde W. (Box 22)
  - Topping, Norman (Dr.) (Box 22)
  - Torch Club (Box 22)
  - Torrey, Volta (Box 22)
  - Totten, Carl E. (Box 29)
  - Town Hall, Incorporated (Box 29)
  - Townsend National Weekly (Box 29)
  - Towson, Sheldon K. (Box 22)
  - Trattner, Ernest R. (Box 22)
  - Trautman, W. D. (Box 22)
  - Treharne, Horace C. (Box 22)
  - Trelease, Sam F. (Box 22)
  - Trinity Cathedral (Box 22)
  - Trombetto, Sunday (Box 22)
  - Truman, Harry S. (Honorable) (Box 22)
  - Tucker, Lawrence A. (Box 22)
  - Tugwell, Rexford G. (Dr.) (Box 22)
  - Tullsen, Stanley A. (Box 22)
  - Turner, Ralph H. (Box 29)
  - Ubell, Earl (Box 22)
  - Udin, Anne (Box 22)
  - Ufford, C. W. (Box 22)
  - Ulmer, J. M. (Box 22)
  - Underhill, C. R. (Box 22)
  - Underwriters' Laboratories (Box 22)
  - UNESCO (Box 22)
  - Union Carbide Corporation (Box 22)
  - Union of American Hebrew Congregations (Box 22)
  - United Broadcasting Company (Box 22)
  - United China Relief (Box 22)
  - United Feature Syndicate (Box 22)
  - United States Atomic Energy Commission (Box 22)
  - United Press (Box 22)
  - United Press Associations (Box 22)
  - United Press International (Box 22)
  - United States Advertising Corporation (Box 23)
  - United States Army (Box 23)
  - United States Atomic Energy Commission (Box 23)
  - United States Coast and Geodetic Survey, W. Bowie (Box 23)
  - United States Department of Agriculture (A. L. Mehring) (Box 23)
  - United States Department of Commerce (Box 23)
  - United States Information Agency (Box 23)
  - United States International Information Administration (Box 23)
  - United States Naval Medical School (Box 23)
  - United States Navy (Box 23)
  - United States Post Office (Box 23)
  - United States Public Health Service (Box 23)
  - United States Rubber Company (Box 23)
  - United States Steel Corporation, 2 folders (Box 23)
  - United States Treasury Department (Box 23)
  - United States Vitamin Corporation (Box 23)
  - United States Weather Bureau, 2 folders (Box 23)
  - United World Federalists of Ohio (Box 23)
  - Universal Jewish Encylopedia (Box 23)
  - University Hospitals (Box 23)
  - University of Arizona (Box 23)
  - University of Bridgeport (Box 23)
  - University of California (Box 23)
  - University of Chicago P. A. (Box 23)
  - University of Chicago Press (Box 23)
  - University of Illinois, 2 folders (Box 23)
  - University of Michigan (Box 23)
  - University of Minnesota (Box 23)
  - University of Notre Dame (Box 23)
  - University of Oklahoma Press (Box 23)
  - University of Pennsylvania, 2 folders (Box 23)
  - University of Pittsburgh (Box 23)
  - University of Pittsburgh School of Medicine (Box 23)
  - University of Rochester (Box 23)
  - University of Texas (Box 23)
  - University of Toledo (Box 23)
  - University of Toronto (Box 23)
  - University of Wisconsin (Box 23)
  - University of Wyoming (Box 23)
    For additional universities, see also Colleges and universities, miscellaneous
  - Upjohn Company (Box 23)
  - Urey, Harold C. (Dr.) (Box 23)
  - Usuline College for Women (Box 23)
  - Van Allen, J. A. (Dr.) (Box 23)
  - Van de Kamp, Peter (Dr.) (Box 23)
  - Van de Water, Marjorie (Box 23)
  - Van Deusen, Alice (Box 23)
  - Van Doren, Carl (Box 23)
  - Van Doren, Irita (Box 23)
  - Vanguard Press (Box 23)
  - Vanik, Charles (Congressman) (Box 23)
  - Van Loon, Hendrik (Box 23)
  - Van Loon, Mrs. Hendrik William (Box 23)
  - Van Nostrand Company (Box 23)
  - Van Riper, Hart E. (Box 23)
  - Van Swerigan, O. P. and M. J. (Box 23)
  - Vanderbilt, Amy (Box 23)
  - Vassar College (Box 23)
  - Vatican Observatory (Box 23)
  - de Vaucoulers, Gerard (Dr.) (Box 23)
  - Veterans Administration (Box 23)
  - Vidal, Eugene L. (Department of Commerce) (Box 23)
  - Viking Press (Box 23)
  - Viking Press, Incorporated (Box 23)
  - Villani, Joseph L. (Box 23)
  - Vinal, William G. (Dr.), 2 folders (Box 23)
  - Vinson, Robert E. (President) (Box 23)
  - Visscher, John Paul (Professor of Biology, V.R.U.) (Box 23)
  - Voss, George P. (Box 23)
  - Wagner, James H. (Box 23)
  - Wagner, C. D. (Box 23)
  - Waldorf-Astoria Hotel (Box 23)
  - Walker, Herbert W. (Box 23)
  - Wall Street Journal (Box 23)
  - Wallace, Henry A. (Box 23)
  - Wallace, Julie Mae (Box 23)
  - Wallace Laboratories (Box 23)
  - Wallenstein, Beatrice (Professor) (Box 23)
  - Walsch, J. Hartt (Dr.) (Box 24)
  - Walter, Paul W. (Box 24)
  - Ward, Patricia Spain (Box 24)
  - Warner, Ethel (Box 24)
  - Warner and Swasey Company (Box 24)
  - Warner and Swasey Observatory (Box 24)
  - Warner-Lambert Pharmaceutical Company, Incorporated (Box 24)
  - Warren Tribune Chronicle (Box 24)
  - Warshawsky, Abel C. (Box 24)
  - Washburne, Carlton (Superintendent, Winnetke Public Schools) (Box 24)
  - Washington, Henry S. (Dr.) (Box 24)
  - Washington Daily News (Box 24)
  - [Ann] Watkins Incorporated (Box 24)
  - Watters, Leon L. (Dr.) (Box 24)
  - Waul, Mildred Ockert (Box 24)
  - Waymack, W. W. (Box 24)
  - Weatherhead Jr., Albert J. (Box 24)
  - Weaver, R. A. (Box 24)
  - Weaver, Wade R. (Box 24)
  - Webber Gage Company (Box 24)
  - Weber, Joseph (Dr.) (Box 24)
  - Weed, Lewis H. (Dr.) (Box 24)
  - Weidlein, Edward R. (Dr.) (Box 24)
  - Weil, Andre L. (Dr.) (Box 24)
  - Weinberger, Adolf (Box 24)
  - Weingarten, L. A. (Box 24)
  - Weisman, Sidney D. (Dr.) (Box 24)
  - Weiss, Edward (Dr.) (Box 24)
  - Weiss, Myron ( Time) (Box 24)
  - Weitz, Sidney N. (Box 24)
  - Weitz Travel Incorporated (Box 24)
  - Weitzmann Institute of Science (Box 24)
  - Welfare Federation of Cleveland (Box 24)
  - Wendt, Gerald (Box 24)
  - Wenner-Gren Foundation (Box 24)
  - Werble, Wallace (Box 24)
  - Wechsler, I. S. (M.D.) (Box 24)
  - Wesleyan University Alumni Council (Box 24)
  - West, Baird F. (Lieutenant) (Box 24)
  - Westchester Cancer Committee (Box 24)
  - Western Publishing Company, Incorporated (Box 24)
  - Western Reserve Academy (Box 24)
  - Western Reserve Kennel Club (Box 24)
  - Western Reserve University (Box 24)
  - Western Union (Box 24)
  - Westinghouse Electric Corporation (Box 24)
  - Weston, Frederick H. (Box 24)
  - Wetzel, Norman C. (Dr.), 2 folders (Box 24)
  - WEWS (television station) (Box 24)
  - Weyerhouser Timber Company (Box 24)
  - Whipple, Fred (Dr.) (Box 24)
  - Wheeler's Review (Box 24)
  - White Motor Company (Box 24)
  - Whiting, Frederic Allen (Box 24)
  - Whittlesey, E. D. (Box 24)
  - Whittlesey House (Box 24)
  - WHK-WCLE (Box 24)
  - Who's Who in America (Box 24)
  - Who's Who in World Jewry (Box 24)
  - Wickendon, William E. (Box 24)
  - Widder, Milton (Box 24)
  - Wiener, Norbert (Box 24)
  - Wiggers, Carl J. (Department of Physiology, Western Reserve University) (Box 24)
  - Wilbur, J. B. (Box 24)
  - [John] Wiley and Sons, Incorporated (Box 24)
  - Wilkes, Daniel M. (Box 24)
  - Wilkin, Robert H. (Judge) (Box 24)
  - Wilkins, Earnest H. (Dr.) (Box 24)
  - Wilkins Lecture (Box 24)
  - Williams, Bob (Box 24)
  - Williams, Frankwood E. (Box 24)
  - Williams, Gordon T. (The Cleveland Tractor Company) (Box 24)
  - Williams, L. B. (Box 24)
  - Williams and Wilkins Company (Box 24)
  - Willis, Delbert (Box 24)
  - Willkie, H. F. (Dr.) (Box 24)
  - Wilmington College (Box 24)
  - Wilson, E. B. (Dr.) (Box 24)
  - [H. W.] Wilson Company (Box 24)
  - Wilson, M. L. (Box 24)
  - Wilson, Sidney S. (Box 24)
  - Wing, Virginia R. (Box 24)
  - Winograd, Maurice A., 2 folders (Box 24)
  - Winter, Ed (Box 25)
  - [John C.] Winston Company (Box 25)
  - Winterick, Bernard (Dr.) (Box 25)
  - Wintner, Alex S. (Box 25)
  - Winton Engine Corporation (Box 25)
  - Wise, H. E. (Box 25)
  - Witt, Fred (Box 25)
  - Witt, Peter (Box 25)
  - Wittke, Carl (Dr.) (Box 25)
  - Wodehouse, H. P. (Box 25)
  - Wolf (Professor), A. (Box 25)
  - Wolfers, Arnold (Dr.) (Box 25)
  - Wolsey, Louis (Rabbi) (Box 25)
  - Wolsey, Louis (Dr.) (Box 25)
  - Women's City Club (Box 25)
  - Wood, Francis Carter (Box 25)
  - Wood, Frederic (Box 25)
  - Wood, Lee (Box 25)
  - Woodward, Ellen S. (Box 25)
  - Worcester Foundation for Experimental Biology (Box 25)
  - Warden, Helen (Box 25)
  - World Almanac (Box 25)
  - World Health Organization (Box 25)
  - World Medical Association (Box 25)
  - World's Fair trip (Box 25)
  - Worldwide Sportsman's Club (Box 25)
  - Wright, Willard (Box 25)
  - Writers Guild of America (Box 25)
  - WVIZ-TV (Box 25)
  - Wyckoff, Ralph W. G. (Box 25)
  - Wylie, C. C. (Professor) (Box 25)
  - Y.M.C.A. (Box 25)
  - Yale University (Box 25)
  - Yanof, Howard M. (Dr.) (Box 25)
  - Yates, Raymond F. (Box 25)
  - Yerkes Observatory (Box 25)
  - York Books, Incorporated (Box 25)
  - Young, Stephen M. (Box 25)
  - Zaller, Morton (Box 25)
  - Zanetti, J. Enrique (Box 25)
  - Zeit, Paul R. (Box 25)
  - Zenith Radio Corporation (Box 25)
  - Zeta Beta Tau (Box 25)
  - Zilboorg, Gregory (Dr.) (Box 25)
  - Zim, Herbert S. (Dr.) (Box 25)
  - Zonta Club of Cleveland (Box 25)
  - Zucker, C. E. (Box 25)
  - Zychick, A. Harry (United States Commissioner General) (Box 25)
- Biographical
  - Autobiography, undated; typescript, 7pg. (Box 29)
  - Autobiographical columns, August 20, 1973-October 19, 1973; 25 columns, typescript (Box 29)
  - Autobiographical columns, Cleveland Press, 1973; 1977; printed material (Box 29)
- Writings
  - Articles
    - Beautiful planet of mystery, c1961; 3 pg. tsc. carbon (Box 29)
    - Bigness of the Universe, c195?; 4 pg, tsc carbon (Box 29)
    - Conquest of space, c1961; 5 pg. tsc. carbon (Box 29)
    - Man on the moon, c195?; 4 pg. tsc. carbon (Box 29)
    - Puzzling giants of the solar system, c1959; 5 pg. tsc. carbon (Box 29)
    - Shooting stars, circa 1960; [5] pg. tsc. carbon (Box 29)
    - Thrilling and mysterious comets, c1960; 4 pg. ts,c, carbon (Box 29)
    - A visit to Earth's twin sister, c195?; 3 pg. tsc. carbon (Box 29)
    - Wonders of the Milky Way, c1959; 3 pg. tsc. carbon (Box 29)
    - Wonders of the Milky Way, c1960; 4 pg. tsq carbon (Box 29)
    - Untitled, unpublished, undated; tsc. carbon, 22 pg. (Box 29)
      Requires permission of donor
  - Books
    - All about the great discoveries in medicine, c1960
      - Typescript, carbon, 109 p. (Box 30)
      - First draft, chapters 2-10 (pg. 6-64), tsc. carbon (Box 30)
      - Suggestions by Dr Harry Goldblatt, tsc. 3 pg. (Box 30)
      - [On polio], tsc. carbon (Box 30)
      - Word list, tsc. carbon, 8 pg. (Box 30)
    - All about satellites and space ships, 1st ed., c1958; chapters 1-16, outline; final manuscript, tsc. carbon (some original pages) with corrections. (Box 30)
    - All about satellites and space ships, rev. ed., c1962
      - 1st draft, tsc. carbon (Box 30)
      - 1st draft, with corrections (Box 30)
      - Revised manuscript, with corrections (Box 30)
      - Author's galleys (Box 30)
    - All about the Universe, c1965
      - Author's proofs (Box 30)
      - Additions (became "Stars and the Universe"), c1968; tsc. carbon (Box 30)
    - Atomic science, bombs and power
      - 1st draft, chapter 9-11, holograph (Box 30)
      - Inserts to first edition (Box 30)
      - Additions to revised edition, holograph (Box 30)
      - Proposed appendix A (Box 30)
      - Galleys (Box 31)
    - " Highlights handbook, exploring space", 1964; additions to revised edition (Box 31)
    - Outline of science
      - "Dead" manuscript, 539 pg, tsc. (Box 31)
      - Tables, tsc (Box 31)
      - Galleys, master set (Box 31)
      - Galleys, master set (Box 32)
      - Galleys, index (Box 32)
      - Galleys, appendix and bibliography (Box 32)
    - New outline of science
      - Manuscript, holograph P & I, Pt. II, Chapter 9-33 (incomplete) (Box 32)
      - 1st draft, chapters 1-25, tsc. (incomplete) (Box 33)
      - Carbon copy, chapters 1-25, tsc, carbon (incomplete) (Box 33)
      - Corrections (Box 33)
      - Index, photocopy of tsc (Box 33)
      - Captions for figures and photographs (Box 33)
      - Captions for figures in text (Box 34)
      - Galleys, master set, pg. i-xii (Box 34)
      - Galleys, author's set (Box 34)
    - Stories of science, corrections to manuscript (Box 34)
  - Lectures
    - "Frontiers of science," Chataugua, NY, July 15-19 1968; (5 lectures, 2 copies (Box 29)
    - "Great books of geology,", Rowfant Club, Cleveland, Ohio, October 8, 1948; tsc. and corrected tsc., each 31 pg. (Box 29)
    - "Great books of science," Rowfant Club, Cleveland, Ohio, October 10, 1947; holo (5 pg.) tsc. (31 pg.) (Box 29)
    - "Great Books of Science," Rowfant Club, Cleveland, Ohio, October 10, 1947; notes on lantern slides, holo, 5 pg. (Box 29)
    - "New Frontiers of science" Chautaugua, NY. Chautauqua, NY, "Sermons", July 20-23, 1964; 4 lectures (Box 29)
- Scrapbooks
  - Sports, 1916 (Package 1)
  - Mirrors of Cleveland, 1922 (Package 1)
  - Story of steel, 1924-1926 (Package 1)
  - Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen's Magazine, 1926 (Package 1)
  - Story of Science, 1926 (Package 1)
  - 1927 (Package 2)
  - 1927-1928 (Package 2)
  - 1929 (Package 2)
  - The Story of Science (Reviews), 1931 (Package 3)
  - 1933, Jan-Aug (Package 4)
  - 1933, Sep-Dec (Package 4)
  - 1934, Jan-Sep (Package 4)
  - 1934, Sep-Dec (Package 4)
  - 1935, Jan-Sep (Package 5)
  - 1936, Jan-Sep (Package 5)
  - 1936, Aug-Dec (Package 5)
  - 1937, Jan-Aug 20 (Package 6)
  - 1937, Aug 21-Dec 31 (Package 6)
  - 1938, Jan-Sep (Package 6)
  - 1938, Oct-Dec (Package 6)
  - Reviews of "Medical Magic", 1937-1938 (Package 7)
  - 1939, Jan-Jul (Package 8)
  - 1939, Aug-Dec (Package 8)
  - 1940, Jan-Sep (Package 8)
  - 1940, Oct-Dec (Package 8)
  - 1941, Jan-Aug (Package 9)
  - 1941, Sep-Dec (Package 9)
  - 1942, Jan-Jun (Package 9)
  - 1942, Jul-Dec (Package 9)
  - 1943, Jan-Jul (Package 10)
  - 1943, Aug-Dec (Package 10)
  - 1944, Jan-Dec (Package 10)
  - Reviews for "Atomic energy in the coming era" by David Deitz, 1945-1947 (Package 11)
  - 1945, Jan-Dec (Package 12)
  - 1945 Dec-1946 Sep (Package 12)
  - 1946 Oct-1947 Jun (Package 12)
  - 1947 Jun-1948 Apr (Package 13)
  - 1948 Apr-Dec (Package 13)
  - 1949 Jan-Sep (Package 13)
  - 1949 Oct-1950 Jul (Package 14)
  - 1950 Aug-1951 May (Package 14)
  - 1951 Jun-1952 Feb (Package 15)
  - 1952 Mar-Dec (Package 15)
  - 1952 Dec-1953 Aug (Package 16)
  - 1953 Sep-1954 Apr (Package 16)
  - 1954 May 3-Dec 31 (Package 16)
  - Reviews of "Atomic Science, Bombs and Power", by David Dietz, 1954-1955 (Package 17)
  - Einstein and polio, 1955 Jan-Aug 15 (Package 18)
  - 1955 Aug 20-1956 May 9 (Package 18)
  - 1956 May 10-1957 Mar 8 (Package 19)
  - 1957 Feb 18-Dec 31 (Package 19)
  - 1958 Jan-Oct 17 (Package 20)
  - 1958 Oct 20-1959 Oct 6 (Package 20)
  - 1959 Oct 6-1960 Aug 29 (Package 21)
  - 1960 Aug 29-1961 May 12 (Package 21)